Roland Levy

Energetic full-stack developer specialising in front-end. Enthusiastic team player and a deep creative thinker with a can-do attitude. Building user-centric, responsive web apps with JavaScript, Vue, React, Node, Express. Will learn whatever language or framework it takes to get the job done.

 LinkedIn:
 linkedin.com/in/roland-levy
 Portfolio:
 rolandlevy.co.uk
 GitHub:
 github.com/rolandjlevy

Skills

Front-end	Back-end	Tooling / workflow
JavaScript, Vue, React,	Node, Express, EJS,	Git, CLI, Bitbucket, Jest, Enzyme,
Angular, Bootstrap	MySQL, Knex, Php	Webpack, Postman, Jira, Agile

Employment & Experience

Ontrack Management Solutions

Full-stack Developer Feb 2019 - Present

- Working with the Systems Architect and other developers to develop and maintain Ontrack MS*
- Developing back-end functionality using Node, Express, Knex and EJS. Writing clean, reusable code
- Building responsive interfaces with Vue.js and some angular.js, Bootstrap, HTML and CSS to meet product and design specifications
- Learning MVC, OOP, Rest APIs and following principles such as YAGNI, KISS, DRY
- Conceptualizing, coding, deploying, and iterating on next generation prototypes. Maintaining legacy code and making improvements to increase readability, reliability and reusability
- Pragmatic approach to analyzing technical issues and clearly communicating solutions

*Ontrack MS provides end-to-end project, job and task tracking with built-in quality management tools. The system takes and stores high resolution photos and videos to provide a visual representation of the quality of workmanship taking place on site. It provides clear communication and full job data including photos, measures, videos, geotags and job history. Visit ontrackms.com

Constructor Labs

Full-Stack JavaScript bootcamp, Sept – Nov 2018

The 12-week bootcamp equipped me with the tools to build interactive, data-driven web applications. I learned and demonstrated complex and sophisticated concepts within JavaScript, React, Redux, Node and Express. In addition, I developed problem-solving, communication and teamwork skills through pair-programming, agile methodologies and self-directed learning. Here are two example projects:

- Better Change (8-day group project) Cashless payment app that uses QR codes for quick, simple charity donations using React, React Router, Redux, Node, Express, PostgreSQL, SCSS
 Live demo: www.betterchange.net | Github: github.com/Benefit-ConstructorLabs/benefit
- OurBnB (4-day group project) Accommodation booking app using React, Node, Express, Handlebars, PostgreSQL, Grid, Flexbox, Twilio

Live demo: ourbnb.herokuapp.com | Github: github.com/OurBnB/OurBnB

Heruka Kadampa Meditation Centre

Administrative Director March 2014 - April 2018

- Managed events, buildings, residents, finances, operations
- Managed all digital & print marketing campaigns. Trained staff to run them
- Managed the design and development of the website. Self-taught JavaScript, PHP, Wordpress

Education Programme Coordinator (EPC) April 2008 - Feb 2014

- Devised and managed programme of over 30 weekly classes & 15 weekend events annually
- Managed the production and distribution of all digital and printed promotional material
- Gained experience in management, communication, problem solving, teamwork

EPC Assistant Feb 2006 - March 2008

- Assisted the management of weekly classes and weekend events
- Supported the EPC with the design and production of print design: Photoshop, Indesign, Illustrator
- Maintained website with Dreamweaver, HTML and CSS

Education

- Diploma in Interactive Multimedia ~ Westminster Kingsway College
- BA Hons Degree in Fine Art, Painting ~ Central Saint Martins College of Art & Design